American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Aug. 30, 1889; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Verein für Erdkunde zu Dresden
    [Dresden], A.L.S.: Paul Emil Richter, Bibliothekar, on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German. Asks for copy of Proceedings, vol.22, No. 119, to supply a gap in his file.
  - Letter to John Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 3, 1889; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Refers to William and Mary college, O.W. Holmes, W.K. Brooks (?), J.S. Price, Max Müller.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Sept. 3, 1889; 10x7-3/4; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Garrisons-on-Hudson [N.Y.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns proof and plates for paper, "Mammals of the Uinta Formation," written by Osborn and W.B. Scott.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 5, 1889; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.: R.W. Young, Asst. Secy. 1p. Enc. of 3p. Sends report of its committee on A.P.S. proposal for congress to study international language. Gives disadvantages of Volapük.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], Sept. 9, 1889; 8x5, 3x5; Washington, Philosophical soc.
    Washington, A.N.S.: W.C. Winlock, Sec. 1p. Enc. Sends receipt of J.J. Sylvester for Proceedings, No.129, sent to them by error.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips [sic], Phila., Sept. 10, 1889; 10x8; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Wm. F. Harrity, Postmaster. 1p. 2 enc. Concerns error in delivery of mail. Encloses fragments of wrapper. Refers to Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 11, 1889; 3x5; Macfarlane, C. W. (Charles William), 1852-1931
    Rosemont, Pa., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for copy of Report on Amended Orthografy.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Sept. 13, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Lee, C. F.
    Alexandria, Va., A.L.S. 1P. and end. Inquires about papers of R.H. Lee in A.P.S. collections.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Sept. 16, 1889; 11x8; Bailey, H. B.
    New York, A.L.S. 1P. and end. wants to purchase copies of the Proceedings, Nos. 91 and 96. Refers to J.L. LeConte and G.H. Horn.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Phila., Sept. 17, 1889; 8x5; Mott, Henry
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. Gives chief officers of McGill College. Refers to Sir D.A. Smith, Sir J.W.Dawson.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Sept. [19], 1889; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Malone, Emily
    Dublin, Printed L. on postal card. 1p., end., and add. Concerns receipt of parts of James Henry's Aeneidea.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 19, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Gregory, Henry D. 1820?-1897
    Girard College, [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Sends his entrance fee in case he cannot attend the meeting.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Sept. 19, 1889; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Royal Dublin Society
    [Dublin], L.S.: Richard J. Moss, Registrar. 2p., end. Concerning list of deficiencies in the A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Sept. 19, 1889; 3x5; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Requests catalogue of publications.
  - Postcard to Henry Phillips, Sept. 19, 1889; Unidentified
    1 Canada Post Card.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Sept. 23, 1889; 5-1/2x8; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Media, Pa.] Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns coming annual meeting of the American Folk-lore Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Sept. 23, 1889; 3x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Media, Pa.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks Phillips to send cards for a committee meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 23, 1889; 3x5; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Garrisons on Hudson, [N.Y.,] A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 24, 1889; 3x5; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about list of Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 25, 1889; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. by E[lla] M[orison]. Concerns proof to be read.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 25, 1889; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Asks for meeting to read proof.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Sept. 26, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of report on A.P.S. Centennial Celebration.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 27, 1889; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Verein für Erdkunde zu Dresden
    Dresden, A.L.S.: [Paul Emil] Richter, Kgl. Bibliothekar, on postal card 1p. and add. In German. Finds he already has Proceedings, No. 119. Apologizes for trouble.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Sept. 30, 1889; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Fulton, John, 1826-1916
    Johnstown, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for another A.P.S. membership certificate, as his was carried away in the flood.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 30, 1889; 3x5; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    [Garrisons, N.Y., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Inquires about proofs.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips [sic], Oct. 1, 1889; 8x5; Biddle, Craig, 1823-1910
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Is ready to read obituary notice of Caspar Wister.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 1, 1889; 10x8; Nova Scotian Institute of Science
    Halifax, N.S., Printed L.S.: J.G. Macgregor, President, and filled in in Ms. 2p., end. Concerns exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 1, 1889; 8-1/4x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns A.P.S. mailing list and other business.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 2, 1889; Columbia University.
    T.L.S. Notifies A.P.S. of perpetual calandar inscribed as "Exhibited at the Centennial Exhibition and presented to the American Philosophical Society...", asks for suggestions on what to do with it.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Oct. 3, 1889; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Concerns his paper, "An Outline of the Philosophy of Evolution."
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 4, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends in a paper for the Proceedings, "The Genus Nyctinomus and a Description of Three New Species."
  - Letter to D[anie]l Kirkwood, Bloomington, Ind., Oct. 4, 1889; 4x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete. Text of letter removed. Written on verso is D. Kirkwood to H. Phillips, Oct. 1889.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Oct. 5, 1889; 10x8; Pennsylvania engraving co. Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: H.A. Gatchel, President. 1p. Concerns H.F. Osborn's proofs and plates.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 5, 1889; 8x5; Pumpelly, Raphael, 1837-1923
    Dublin, N.H., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his subscription.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 7, 1889; 8-1/4x5-3/4; Biddle, Arthur, 1852-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his address. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 7, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Teikoku Toshokan (Japan)
    Tokyo, A.L.S.: S. Suyeoka, Director. 1p., end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Oct. 7, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Keyes, Charles Rollin, 1864-1942
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p., and add., end. Inquires about proofs of his paper on Platyceras.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 8, 1889; 3x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S.: P. DB. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns H.V. Hilprecht.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Oct. 8, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Encloses letter of thanks from Andover theological seminary. Refers to paper on Platycerata by C.R. Keyes. For enclosure, see Andover theological seminary to H. Phillips, Oct. 15, 1889.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 8, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Lea Brothers & Company
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 9, 1889; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his paper on "Ethnologic Affinities of the Ancient Etruscans." Refers to meeting of the American Folklore Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 9, 1889; 11-1/4x8-3/4; Köhler, Friedrich Eugen
    Gera-Untermhaus, L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting In German Asks for specimens in order to complete a botanical work.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 9, 1889; 3x5; Pumpelly, Raphael, 1837-1923
    Dublin, N.H., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Concerns his address.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 11, 1889; 8x5; Biddle, Craig, 1823-1910
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting "How shall I answer the enclosed?"
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 11, 1889; 3x5; Columbia University. Superintendent's office
    New York, L. on postal card. 1p., end., and add., end. Will send the perpetual calendar as requested by Phillips.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1889; 3x5; Burk, Jesse Young, ca. 1840-1904
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card. 1p., end., and add., end. Prof. E.J. James has returned to his duties.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1889; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end., and add. Concerns dues of Elihu Thomson.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 12, [1889]; 6-3/4x4-4/2; Patterson, Christopher Stuart, 1842-1924
    Gracehill, A.L.S. 2p. Will prepare obituary of Frank Thomson.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 13, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Ford, Worthington Chauncey, 1858-1941
    Brooklyn N.Y., A.L.S. 2p., and end. Asks permission to work with R.H.Lee papers in A.P.S. collection.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 14, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Concerns his address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 15, 1889; 8x5; Andover Theological Seminary
    A.L.S.: W.L. Ropes, Librarian. 2p. Thanks for gift of publications. Will exchange what little they publish.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1889; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Biblioteca nazionale centrale di Firenze
    Firenze, L. 1p., end. In Italian. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 15, 1889; 10x7-3/4; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Asks about size of edition of the Transactions.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Oct. 15, 1889; 3x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns Elihu Thomson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 18, 1889; 9-1/2x6, 11x8-1/2; Landreth, Burnet, 1842-1928
    Bristol, Pa., L.S. 2p. Enc. Asks A.P.S. to join Association of Centenary Firms and Corporations of the U.S. Sends copy of articles of association which carry partly erased notes by C.G. Sower.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 19, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Ford, Worthington Chauncey, 1858-1941
    Brooklyn N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end. Makes appointment to work on R.H. Lee papers in A.P.S. collection.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 22, 1889; 10x8; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Henry Drake, Assistant Postmaster. 1p. Enc. wanting. Concerns delay in mail delivery.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 23, 1889; 3x5; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Refers to [Cope's?] paper. Evolution.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 25, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Kansas Academy of Science
    Topeka, Kansas, A.L.S.: B.B. Smyth, Librarian. 1p. 2 enc. wanting. Sends receipts for Noss 127, 128 of Proceedings.
  - Letter to H[enry] P[hillips], Jr., Oct. 25, 1889; 3x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Refers to A. de Gregorio, L.F. Ward, A.A. Blair.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 25, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Stanton, Irving G.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Recommends Rev. Albert Lee for library position.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Oct. 29, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns reconstruction of A.P.S. Hall.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 29, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Photo Engraving Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Will close Philadelphia office.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 30, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Lesquereaux, Leo, Jr.
    Columbus, O., Printed L. 1p. Announces death of his father.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 31, 1889; 3x5; Bailey, H. B.
    Newport News, Va., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end. and add. Concerns purchase of publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 31, 1889; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Gray, Henry
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns lists of deficiencies in A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Oct. 31, 1889; 5-3/4x9; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Refers to American Folklore Society. On verso of sheet is Price's reply. See J.S. Price to H. Phillips, Nov. 1, 1889.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct., 1889; 4x5-3/4; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends stamps and a change of address. Date added in H. Phillips' hand. Written on verso of incomplete letter. See H. Phillips to D. kirkwood, Oct. 4, 1889.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], Nov. 1, 1889; 11x8-1/2; New York engraving and printing co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Philadelphia branch is now open.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], Nov. 1, 1889; 5-3/4x9; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Written on verso of letter from Phillips See H. Phillips to J.S. Price, Oct. 31, 1889.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 1, 1889; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, L.S.: Alvey A. Adee, 2nd Assistant Secretary. 1p., end. 2 enc. wanting. Transmits 2 copies of "Flora Batava", Nos. 285, 286.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jr., Nov. 2, 1889; 6x4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of his remarks.
  - Letter to [J. Peter] Lesley, Nov. 4, 1889; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hall, S. M.
    Albany, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end. by J.P.L. Concerns engraver of the Iowa Report, James Duthie.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Nov. 4, 1889; 8x5; Williams, H.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks price of Proceedings for 1887, 1888.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 5, 1889; 7x5-1/2; Pennsylvania engraving co. Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: H.A. Gatchel. 1p. 2 enc. Sends 2 proofs of drawings for paper by Ryder.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 5, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Pennsylvania engraving co. Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: H.A. Gatchel, President. 1p. Concerns drawings for J.A. Ryder's paper
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 7, 1889; 10x8; Harding, George, 1826?-1902
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends his photograph for A.P.S. Album.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 8, 1889; 8x5; Andover Theological Seminary
    Andover, Mass., A.L.S.: W.L. Ropes, Librarian. 2p. end. Sends some of its publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 8, [1889]; 8x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Media, Pa.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns nominations for A.P.S. offices.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sargeant [sic] Price, Nov. 9, 1889; 9-3/4x7; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, O., Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot attend A.P.S. centennial celebration.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 9, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Torrey, D.
    Detroit, Mich., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Requests copy of report on amended orthography.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Nov. 13, 1889; 9x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will write obituary of Leo Lesquereaux.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 14, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Rogers, William Barton, 1833-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends report of Finance Committee.
  - Note to Henry Phillips, Nov. 15, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Phillips, Emily
    [Phila.,] A.N. in 3d person 1p., end., and add. Gift of newspapers to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Nov. 15, [1889]; 7x4-1/2; Nadaillac, Jean-François-Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends receipt for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 18, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Chollar, T. T.
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. Offers files of N.Y. newspapers for sale.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 18, 1889; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Nov.18, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Davenport Academy of Natural Sciences
    Davenport, Iowa, A.L.S.:W.H.Pratt, curator. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of publication from Society. Attached to same sheet is letter from Davenport academy of natural sciences to APS, June 5, 1889.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Nov. 20, 1889; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Boldt, George C., 1851-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Written on verso of sheet is letter, J.S. Price to H. Phillips, [Nov. 1889]
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Nov. 20, 1889; 6-1/4x4; De Gregorio, Antonio, marchese, 1855-1930
    Palermo, A.L.S. 2p. Acknowledges receipt of Proceedings. Refers to Annales de géologie et de paléontologie, and to Charles Clausen.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 20, 1889; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Written on verso of letter from G.C. Boldt to J.S. Price, Nov. 20, 1889.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Nov. 23, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks him for Plaque (?).
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 23, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Mallet, John William
    University of Virginia, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends typescript of his remarks at A.P.S. centennial celebration.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 23, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Riché, George Inman, 1833-1909
    [Detroit, Mich.], A.L.S. 1p. and end. Resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 23, 1889; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Washington, Typed L.S.: H[enry] W[etherbee] Henshaw. 2p. Inquires about Lewis and Clark manuscript Indian vocabularies. Refers to B.S. Barton, Historical Society of Penna.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 25, 1889; 8-1/4x5-1/4; De Gregorio, Antonio, marchese, 1855-1930
    Palermo, Italy, A.L.S. 1p. Sends his photograph.
  - Letter to Harrison Allen, Nov. 26, 1889; 9-1/4x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., L. 1p. and end. Concerns extras of his article.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 27, 1889; 3x5; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will read paper on Carollia at next meeting.
  - Letter to [Harrison] Allen, Nov. 27, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Has told MacCalla & Co. to send him another proof.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 28, 1889; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Geological Society of London
    [London], A.L.S.: W.S. Dallas, Assistant Secretary 3p. and end. Sends certain publications to fill gap in A.P.S. file, Asks for A.P.S. publications to complete its file.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 28, 1889; 3x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks for addresses of W.S.W. Ruschenberger and R.D. Wood.
  - Notice of consignment shipped to A.P.S., Nov. 28, 1889; 8-3/4 x10-1/4; Wheatley, George W. & co.
    London, Printed D. filled in in MS. 2p.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Nov. 29, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Refers to his address at the centennial celebration. Refers to various appointments and A.P.S. matters.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 29, 1889; 8x5; Goode, G. Brown (George Brown), 1851-1896
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for pamphlets. Refers to A.P.S. centennial celebration.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 30, 1889; 8x5-1/4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. About printing of his papers.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Nov. 30, 1889; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Parnell, L. & J.
    London, L. on postal card 1p. and add. Bookseller's quotations.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 2, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends MS. of his address at A.P.S. Centennial celebration.
  - Letter to the Secretary, American Philosophical Society [Henry Phillips], Dec. 2, 1889; 8x5; Royal Society of Victoria (Melbourne, Vic.)
    Melbourne, A.L.S.: London Cattlin, Asst. Secry. 2p., end. About publications of the Royal society of Victoria.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], December 2, 1889; Royal Society of Victoria (Melbourne, Vic.)
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 3, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires if plates have arrived from Germany.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 3, 1889; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Finance Committee. Refers to D.G. Brinton.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 3, 1889; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Refers to various reports, plate of the Hall.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 4, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Poor, Henry V. (Henry Varnum), 1812-1905
    N.Y., Mimeo. L. 1p. Offers various publications for sale.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philips [sic], Dec. 5, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Dolley, Charles S.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Requests loan of a number of books from the A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Dec. 7, 1889; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copies of "Dinner" number of Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 9, 1889; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Goode, G. Brown (George Brown), 1851-1896
    Washington, Typed L.S. 2p.,end. Inquires about letter by Franklin on the origin of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 9, 1889; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Phila, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from Museum d'Histoire Naturelle, Paris, acknowledging receipt of photographs of American trees.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 9, 1889; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Monier-Williams, Monier, Sir, 1819-1899
    London, A.N. in 3d person. 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 10, 1889; 3x5; Hempstead, O. G. & son
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Business matter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 12, 1889; 4x5-1/2; Eames, Wilberforce, 1855-1937
    N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Asks about A.P.S. copies of Eliot Indian Bible.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Hempstead, O. G. & son
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end.: London Geol. Socy. Concerns shipment of books from England
  - Letter to [Johann] Japetus [Smith] Steenstrup, Copenhagen, Dec. 14, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy by E[lla] M[orison]. Thanks for offer to send lacking nos. of Memoirs of Royal Danish Academy of Sciences.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 14, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for biographical note on Jean Dassier of Geneva, mentioned in Du Simitière's note book.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society [Henry Phillips], Dec. 16, 1889; 10 1/2 x8 1/2; Peñafiel, Antonio, 1831-1922